Guide to the Small Manuscript Collections
The Wittliff Collections
Small Manuscript Collections
Multiple Dates
The Wittliff Collections
SWWC.150
12 Linear Feet
Small Manuscript Collections consists of material acquired by the Wittliff either through gift or purchase that are not part of a larger collection. They are often indiidual items or small groups of items relating to a particular author, musician, photographer, or topic. Types of material include: manuscripts; letters; photographs; ephemera such as pamphlets, brouchures or cataloges; reports; historical documents; and other printed material. Each item or group of items is assigned a unique number such as SMC-0001, SMC-0002, SMC-0003, etc. that serves as the call number for the respective small collection.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Collection Overview
Small Manuscript Collections consists of material acquired by the Wittliff either through gift or purchase that are not part of larger collections. They are often indiidual items or small groups of items relating to a particular author, musician, photographer, or topic. Types of material include: manuscripts; letters; photographs; ephemera such as pamphlets, brouchures or cataloges; reports; historical documents; and other printed material. Each item or group of items is assigned a unique number such as SMC-0001, SMC-0002, SMC-0003, etc. that serves as the call number for the respective small collection.
Acquisition Information
Information not available.
- William H. Goetzmann manuscript, undated; Goetzmann, William H.
  Mexican-American border region; Emory, William H. (William Hemsley), 1811-1887
  - Manuscript by William Goetzmann of introduction to William H. Emory Report on the United States and Mexican Boundary Survey published in a Texas State Historical Association reprint of the Emory report., undated (Folder SMC 0001)
- W. Thomas Taylor collection, 1976-1988; Taylor, W. Thomas
  Publishers and publishing -- Texas
  - Broadsides and ephemera printed by publisher, printer, and antiquarian bookseller W. Thomas Taylor. Includes new book announcements, catalogues, business promotional material, programs, poetry, personal announcements, and a page proof., 1976-1988 (Folder SMC 0002)
- Horton Foote collection, 1983-1987; Foote, Horton
  Screenplays
  - Copy of screenplay "Nineteen Eighteen," Signed, 101 typed pages, August 2, 1983 (Folder SMC 0003)
  - Publicity booklet for "The Trip to the Bountiful." 8 leaves, signed (Folder SMC 0003)
  - Typed copy of Foote's vita, 1 page (Folder SMC 0003)
- John C. Duval letter, July 30, 1856; Duval, John C. (John Crittenden), 1816-1897
  Fort Bend County (Tex.) -- History; Fulshear, Churchill
  - Letter from John C. Duval to Churchill Fulshea, July 30, 1856 (Folder SMC 0004)
- Noah Smithwick records, 1840; Donaldson, Nanna Smithwick; Hancock, William R.
  Republic of Texas -- History; Smithwick, Noah, 1808-1899
  - "Biographical sketch of the author" by Nanna Smithwick Donaldson about Noah Smithwick. 1 page, handwritten., undated (Folder SMC 0005)
  - Legal document written by William R. Hancock, acting justice of the peace in Bastrop County, Republic of Texas. Document concerns Noah Smithwick and William A. Clapton who provided sworn statements as to the value of a horse captured by the Comanches. 1 page, handwritten., April 23, 1840 (Folder SMC 0005)
- Ancel Nunn drawing, circa 1969; Nunn, Ancel E.
  Artists -- Texas; Greene, A. C., 1923-2002
  - Original pen and ink preliminary drawing by Ancel Nunn for "A Personal Country" by A.C. Greene, circa 1969 (Folder SMC 0006)
- W. Thomas Taylor collection on Gertrude Beasley, 1989; Taylor, W. Thomas
  Teachers -- Texas; Beasley, Gertrude
  - Souvenir booklet for meeting of the Book Club of Texas containing a reprint of H.L. Mencken's review of My First Thirty Years by Gertrude Beasley, titled "A Texas Schoolmarm" which originally appeared in the January 1926 issue of The American Mercury., November 4, 1989 (Folder SMC 0007)
  - Page proofs for 1989 edition of My First Thirty Years, printed by W. Thomas Taylor for the Austin Book Club. Missing pp. 236-237 and colophon. Included are the title page and two sheets of uncut proofs. (Folder SMC 0007)
- Ace Reid photograph with J. Frank Dobie, undated
  Authors, American -- Texas; Reid, Asa E., 1925-1991; Dobie, J. Frank (James Frank), 1888-1964
  - Black and white photograph of Ace Reid with J. Frank Dobie at a book signing, undated (Folder SMC 0008)
- Robert (Bob) Wade collection, 1984-1990; Wade, Bob (Robert Schrope), 1943-2019
  Artists -- Texas
  - Resume, 26 typed pages, signed, 1984 (Folder SMC 0009)
  - "Bob Wade: Projects and Photoworks", a promotional booklet for a show, including a signed pen and ink self-portrait on the title page, 1984 (Folder SMC 0009)
  - Announcement for "Bob Wade: Photo Works" exhibition with handwritten note to Bill Wittliff, 1990 (Folder SMC 0009)
  - Two cards featuring Wade's original artwork (Folder SMC 0009)
  - Postcard to Encino Press in Austin, Texas announcing an exhibition, 1990 (Folder SMC 0009)
  - Letter from Stephen Nagy to Bob Wade, April 12, 1990 (Folder SMC 0009)
  - Photocopies of articles discussing Wade's work (Folder SMC 0009)
  - Complete issues of Pasatiempo and The Santa Fean Magazine (Folder SMC 0009)
  - Flyer from Posters of Santa Fe featuring Wade's art (Folder SMC 0009)
  - Handmade Christmas card to the Wittliff family from Bob and Lisa Wade, 1987 (Folder SMC 0009)
- John H. Jenkins collection, 1966-1990; Jenkins, John Holmes
  - Signed note from author and publisher John H. Jenkins to Bill Wittliff written on a copy of "Why minors should vote", by John Jenkins, published in the December 1957 American Mercury, May 2, 1966 (Folder SMC 0010)
  - Complete copy of December 1957 American Mercury with a letter from Jenkins to Bill Wittliff written on the second page, April 25, 1966 (Folder SMC 0010)
  - Paperback copy of "The General's Tight Pants: Edward Warren's Texas Tour of 1836" ed. by John H. Jenkins, sent as a Christmas greeting, 1976 (Folder SMC 0010)
  - Paperback of "Robert E. Lee on the Rio Grande: The Corrospondence of Robert E. Lee on the Texas Border, 1860" ed. by John H. Jenkins, and published by the Jenkins Publishing Company. Sent as a Christmas greeting, with original envelope, 1988 (Folder SMC 0010)
  - Paperback of "Memoir of Capt'n C. R. Perry of Johnson City, Texas, a Texas Veteran", ed. by Kenneth Kesselus, published by the Jenkins Publishing Company and sent as a Christmas greeting, 1990 (Folder SMC 0010)
- Webb family collection on Jose Cisneros, 1970-1983; Cisneros, José, 1910-2009
  Mexican American artists -- Texas; Artists -- Texas
  - Exhibit notices and copies of news clippings from artist Jose Cisneros. Includes 3 handwritten notes from Cisneros to Bridget and Wilfred Webb., 1970-1983 (Folder SMC 0011)
- Sarah Bird interview with Dave Hickey transcript, 1993; Bird, Sarah
  Authors, American -- Texas; Authors -- Interviews; Hickey, Dave, 1940-
  - Typed transcript of Sarah Bird's Spring 1993 interview with Dave Hickey. Includes a typed note from transcriber Sarah Lowry. (Folder SMC 0012)
- Michael Hall interview transcripts, 1993; Hall, Michael
  Authors, American -- Texas; Wright, Lawrence, 1947-; Bird, Sarah; Harrigan, Stephen, 1948-; King, Larry L.
  - Transcript of interview by Michael Hall with Steve Harrigan, Larry Wright, and Sarah Bird. Typed with edits in pen. Transcribed by Sarah Lowry, March 1, 1993 (Folder SMC 0013)
  - Transcript of interview by Michael Hall with Larry L. King. Typed with edits in pen. Transcribed by Sarah Lowry, April 12, 1993 (Folder SMC 0013)
- Edwin "Bud" Shrake manuscript, Harvey Penick's Little Red Book, 1991; Shrake, Edwin
  Golf -- United States -- Anecdotes; Penick, Harvey
  - Original typed manuscript with editing notations for Harvey Penick's Little Red Book lessons and teachings from a lifetime in golf by Harvey Penick with Bud Shrake, published 1992. Includes typesetting and design material, a letter to Shrake from the publisher, and a note to Bill Wittliff from Shrake. Manuscript is approximately 196 pages., 1991 (Folder SMC 0014)
- Edwin "Bud" Shrake draft, And If You Play Golf, You're my Friend, 1993; Shrake, Edwin
  - Edwin "Bud" Shrake draft, And If You Play Golf, You're my Friend, 1993 (Folder SMC 0015)
- Willie Morris collection, 1993; Morris, Willie
  Shrake, Edwin; Richards, Ann, 1933-2006
  - Handwritten letter from Willie Morris to Bud Shrake, August 1, 1993 (Folder SMC 0016)
  - Photocopy of letter from Governor Ann Richards to Willie Morris (Folder SMC 0016)
  - Three clippings discussing Willie Morris' writing (Folder SMC 0016)
- J. Rhett Rushing manuscript, 1993; Rushing, J. Rhett
  Horse trading -- Texas
  - Typed manuscript of "Horsetrading and Ethics" by J. Rhett Rushing, 1993 (Folder SMC 0017)
- Joe Holley collection, 1993; Holley, Joe, 1946-
  Authors, American -- Texas; Mexican American authors -- Texas; Paredes, Américo, 1915-1999
  - Typed copy of Austin Chronicle article by Joe Holley about author Americo Paredes, October 15, 1993 (Folder SMC 0018)
- Mary Brown McSwain manuscripts, 1991; McSwain, Mary Brown, 1911-
  Women missionaries -- Brazil -- Biography
  - Spiral bound typed copies of "My Adventures with Transportation", part 6, March 7, 1991 (Folder SMC 0019)
  - Spiral bound typed copies of "My Adventures with Transportation", part 7, July 5, 1991 (Folder SMC 0019)
- Don Graham collection on The Gay Place, 1994; Graham, Don, 1940-
  Texas -- Politics and government -- Fiction; Brammer, Billy Lee
  - Two typed drafts of Don Graham's introduction to The Gay Place: Being Three Related Novels by Billy Lee Brammer, 1994 (Folder SMC 0020)
  - Cover for new edition of The Gay Place, 1994 (Folder SMC 0020)
- Don Graham collection on Pretty Boy Floyd, 1994; Graham, Don, 1940-
  Authors, American; Graham, Don, 1940-; McMurtry, Larry; Ossana, Diana
  - Press release for Pretty Boy Floyd by Larry McMurtry and Diana Ossana, 1994 (Folder SMC 0021)
  - Article titled "The Authors Talk About Their Collaboration", 1994 (Folder SMC 0021)
- Scott Slovic interview with Rick Bass, Fall 1994; Slovic, Scott, 1960
  Authors -- Interviews; Bass, Rick
  - Weber Studies: An Interdisciplinary Humanities Journal, edited by Scott Slovic and Neila C. Seshachari. First page is signed with a note from Scott Slovic. Includes Slovic's interview with Rick Bass titled "A Paint Brush in One Hand and a Bucket of Water in the Other: Nature Writing and the Politics of Wilderness.", Fall 1994 (Folder SMC 0022)
- Brandt Andrew Rydell thesis, 1994; Rydell, Brandt Andrew
  African American rodeo performers; Pickett, Bill, approximately 1860-1932
  - Honors thesis "The Dusky Demon: Profile of a Black Rodeo Cowboy" about Bill Pickett. Submitted in partial fulfillment of the requirements of honors studies in history at J. Fullbright College of Arts and Sciences, Spring 1994 (Folder SMC 0023)
- Texas ephemera collection, 1936-1986; Toler, Terry
  Rodeos; Toler, Terry
  - Program for "Waldemar Rodeo and Round-up, final banquet", August 27, 1942 (Folder SMC 0024)
  - "Texas and the Centennial" booklet, Dallas, 1936-1986 (Folder SMC 0024)
  - "Texas in Transition: A Sesquicentennial Forum", program, April 18, 1986 (Folder SMC 0024)
  - Blank notepad with cover design depicting a cowboy riding a wild horse (Folder SMC 0024)
- Robert Sparkman collection on Jose Cisneros, 1967-1987; Sparkman, Robert S.
  Artists -- Texas; Mexican American artists -- Texas; Cisneros, José, 1910-2009; Sparkman, Robert S.
  - Correspondence with artist Jose Cisneros. Some letter and notes are written on news clipping and publications containing his art (Folder SMC 0025)
  - Complete issue of Southwestern Art V. 4 no. 4 containing an article about Cisneros (Folder SMC 0025)
  - Catalog for Michael Gibbs, bookseller containing an original illustration by Cisneros (Folder SMC 0025)
  - American Book Collector V. 23 no. 2 with cover illustration by Cisneros (Folder SMC 0025)
  - El Paso Magazine, containing original illustration by Cisneros, December 1973 (Folder SMC 0025)
  - Program for the 21st annual conference of the Texas Council for the Social Studies with illustration and script by Cisneros (Folder SMC 0025)
  - El Paso Physician with cover illustration by Cisneros (Folder SMC 0025)
  - Program for the United States Military Academy Library exhibit featuring Cisneros, containing and original drawing (Folder SMC 0025)
  - Cover for "Death Was the Black Horse" by Dale L. Walker, with cover illustration by Cisneros (Folder SMC 0025)
  - Cover for "Teresita" by William Curry Holden, illustrated by Cisneros (Folder SMC 0025)
  - Program for "Jose Cisneros at Paisano" from the Institute of Texan Cultures, University of Texas System, July 1969 (Folder SMC 0025)
- Robert Sparkman collection on M.T. "Lone Wolf" Gonzaullas, 1966; Sparkman, Robert S.; Gonzaullas, Manuel Trazazas, 1891-1977
  Texas Rangers; Sparkman, Robert S.; Gonzaullas, Manuel Trazazas, 1891-1977
  - Three black and white photographs of Texas Ranger M.T. "Lone Wolf" Gonzaullas, inscribed to Sparkman (Folder SMC 0026)
  - Aldredge Book Store advertisement publicizing he purchase of Gonzaullas's book collection, with handwritten note from Gonzaullas to Sparkman (Folder SMC 0026)
  - Post card with color photograph of Gonzaullas (Folder SMC 0026)
  - Blank copy of Ranger Daily Scout Report (Folder SMC 0026)
  - Pamphlet titled "Texas Rangers" from the Texas Department of Public Safety (Folder SMC 0026)
- Robert Sparkman collection on David W. Guion, 1970-1972; Sparkman, Robert S.
  Composers--Texas; Cowboys -- Songs and music; Sparkman, Robert S.; Guion, David W. (David Wendell)
  - Program from "The Songs of David W. Guion" at the Baylor School of Music", June 25, 1971 (Folder SMC 0027)
  - Pamphlet titled " The music of David Guion" (Folder SMC 0027)
  - Clippings related Guion, some original newsprint (Folder SMC 0027)
  - Correspondence between Sparkman and Guion, 1970-1971 (Folder SMC 0027)
  - Typed copy of lyrics to "Mary Alone"--words by Lucile Isabell Stall, music by David W. Guion (Folder SMC 0027)
  - Black and white photograph of Guion, inscribed to Sparkman (Folder SMC 0027)
  - Musical score and lyrics to "Home of the Range", handwritten by Guion and inscribed to Sparkman, July 1971 (Folder SMC 0027)
- Luis Guillermo Guerra solar plate, undated; Guerra, Luis Guillermo
  Artists -- Texas; Mexican American artists -- Texas
  - One of the 45 pieces of of the solar plate etching used to make the print Omecihuatl, undated (Folder SMC 0028)
- Robert Sparkman correspondence with Ralph Yarborough, 1970-1995; Sparkman, Robert S.
  Postage stamp design; Sparkman, Robert S.; Yarborough, Ralph Webster, 1903-1996
  - Cards and letters between Ralph Yarborough and Robert Sparkman including two printings of a Christmas pamphlet containing Yarborough's speech on the dedication of the Sam Houston stamp. The pamphlet was designed by Bill Wittliff and published by Encino Press. The stamp was designed by Tom Lea. Pamphlet is signed by Wittliff, Lea, and Ralph and Opal Yarborough, 1970-1995 (Folder SMC 0029)
  - Correspondence between Robert Sparkman and Tom and Sarah Lea, 1995 (Folder SMC 0029)
  - Letters to Bill Wittliff, 1993-1995 (Folder SMC 0029)
- Clay Reynolds collection of book covers and ephemera, undated; Reynolds, Clay, 1949
  Book design; Reynolds, Clay, 1949
  - New Growth 2 ed. Mark Busby (Folder SMC 0030)
  - New Growth ed. by Lyman Grant (2 copies) (Folder SMC 0030)
  - This Place of Memory, A Texas Perspective ed. by Joyce Gibson Roach (Folder SMC 0030)
  - Promotional flyer for Streets of Laredo, by Larry McMurtry (Folder SMC 0030)
- Elmer Kelton "John Graves Day" address, 1995; Kelton, Elmer
  Speeches, addresses, etc.; Graves, John, 1920-2013
  - Two copies of typescript for Elmer Kelton's address at "John Graves Day" held at the Dallas Museum of Art, March 4, 1995 (Folder SMC 0031)
- A. C. Greene "John Graves Day" address, 1995; Greene, A. C., 1923-2002
  - Two drafts of Greene's address for "John Graves Day" held at the Dallas Museum of Art, March 4, 1995 (Folder SMC 0032)
- Don Graham "John Graves Day" draft, 1995; Graham, Don, 1940-
  Graves, John, 1920-2013
  - Draft of Graham's address for "John Graves Day", held at the Dallas Museum of Art, March 4, 1995 (Folder SMC 0033)
- David Rice typescripts and ephemera, undated; Rice, David (1964-)
  Authors, American -- Texas
  - "The Circumstances Surrounding My Penis," by David Rice. Typescript, undated (Folder SMC 0034)
  - "El Sapo," by David Rice. Typescript, undated (Folder SMC 0034)
  - Promotional postcard signed by David Rice with note to Steve Davis, undated (Folder SMC 0034)
- James E. Crisp "Texas History, Texas Mystery" article, 1995; Crisp, James E., 1946-
  Crockett, Davy, 1786-1836
  - Photocopy of Crisp's notes and two drafts for his essay "Texas History, Texas Mystery" which was published in Sallyport: The Magazine of Rice University. Complete issue of the magazine, with Crisp's picture on the cover included., February/March 1995 (Folder SMC 0035)
- John Slate Zine Collection, 1980-1984; Slate, John H.
  Description
  Magazines and zines related to Austin's punk music scene of the early 1980's
  Punk rock music; Music -- Texas -- Periodicals; Zines; Slate, John H.
  - Peligro! (2 issues), undated (Folder SMC 0036)
  - The Western Roundup (2 issues), circa 1982 (Folder SMC 0036)
  - Xiphoid Process (14 issues), 1980-1984 (Folder SMC 0036)
- Mike Daily collection on Harold W. "Pappy" Daily, 1959-1995; Daily, Mike
  Music -- Texas; Country music; Daily, Mike; Daily, Pappy, 1902-
  - Clipping and ephemera relating to the career of record producer Harold W. "Pappy" Daily, 1959-1995 (Folder SMC 0037)
- Eugene Lee typescripts, 1992-1994; Lee, Eugene
  Theater; African American authors
  - "Fear Itself" (play) by Eugene Lee. 5th draft typescript, May 21, 1994 (Folder SMC 0038)
  - Letter from Eugene Lee to March, November 4, 1994 (Folder SMC 0038)
  - Copy of Eugene Lee's resume (Folder SMC 0038)
  - "Guardian Angel", by Eugene Lee, dated, June 22, 1992 (Folder SMC 0038)
- F. E. Abernethy address, 1995; Abernethy, Francis Edward
  Speeches, addresses, etc.
  - Typescript of F. E. Abernethy's address at the opening of the exhibition, "No Traveler Remains Untouched," at the Longview Public Library, July 20, 1995 (Folder SMC 0039)
- Willie Nelson's 4th of July Picnic program, 1995; Luckenbach Texas, Inc.
  Music festivals -- Texas; Nelson, Willie, 1933-
  - Volume 2, Issue 6 of the Luckenbach Moon, also the "Offishul Souvineer Program" of Willie Nelson's annual 4th of July Picnic in Luckenbach, Texas, July 1995 (Folder SMC 0040)
- Lawrence Clark Powell letter, 1971; Powell, Lawrence Clark, 1906-2001
  - Photocopy of Powell's letter to the editor of American Libraries complaining about an essay the magazine published, April 20, 1971 (Folder SMC 0041)
- Larry L. King articles, circa 1952; King, Larry L.
  - Game-Caller News, volume 1, number 1. Contains three articles by Larry L. King --one under his own name (p. 2), one under the pseudonym Gaylord M. Brooks (p. 1), and one under the pseudonym Ransom Jackson (p. 3) (Folder SMC 0042)
- Mary Winfield McComb collection on Alfred Benjamin Fontaine Kerr, 1898-1939; McComb, Mary Winfield
  Series Description
  Documents relating to Alfred Benjamin Fontaine Kerr, Methodist minister and first mayor of San Marcos
  San Marcos (Tex.) -- History; Methodist Church -- Texas -- Clergy; McComb, Mary Winfield; Kerr, Alfred Benjamin Fontaine
  - Photographs of Alfred B. F. Kerr, his wife, and daugher, Lucy (Folder SMC 0043)
  - Letters from S. M. Sewell to Kerr's surviving relatives looking for biographical information about Alfred Kerr for the First Methodist Church's 91st anniversary (program included), 1898-1939 (Folder SMC 0043)
  - "Kerr Family History" taken from the Texas Christian Advocate, May 10, 1917 (Folder SMC 0043)
  - Photocopy of Kerr "Family group record" (Folder SMC 0043)
  - Letter whose author and recipient are unknown (Folder SMC 0043)
  - Certification from Mayor Sam Kone that Kerr was the mayor as of July 1877 (Folder SMC 0043)
- Cora and Gilbert McAllister correspondence, 1963-1969
  Wheeler, Kenneth W.; Stilwell, Hart, 1902-1975
  - Correspondence between Cora and Gilbert McAllister and Kenneth Wheeler and Hart Stilwell, 1963-1969 (Folder SMC 0044)
  - Review of Kenneth Wheeler's book "To Wear a City's Crown" (Folder SMC 0044)
- Kinky Friedman article on Willie Nelson, circa 1990; Friedman, Kinky
  Nelson, Willie, 1933-
  - Typescript of Kinky Friedman magazine profile of Willie Nelson (Folder SMC 0045)
- Colin Short drawing and ephemera, 1991; Short, Colin
  King, Larry L.; Jones, Tommy Lee, 1946-; Albert B. Alkek Library
  - Original drawing by Colin Short of Larry L. King, 1991 (Folder SMC 0046)
  - Promotional materials for Tommy Lee Jones' television film "The Good Old Boys", 1991 (Folder SMC 0046)
  - Slides and an announcement for Tommy Lee Jones' appearance at the Southwest Texas State University Alkek Library, 1991 (Folder SMC 0046)
- Thomas R. Hester essays, 1989-1992; Hester, Thomas R.
  Excavations (Archaeology) -- Texas
  - "Indians and Missions in Northern Coahuila and Southern Texas" Photocopy (Folder SMC 0047)
  - Introduction to Archeological Studies of South Texas Indian Groups of the 14th to 18th Centuries A.D." Photocopy (Folder SMC 0047)
- Donald W. Olson article, 1997; Olson, Donald W.
  Núñez Cabeza de Vaca, Alvar, active 16th century
  - "Pinon pines and the route of Cabeza de Vaca", by Donald W. Olson et. al. submitted to the Southwestern Historical Quarterly. Typescript, 1997 (Folder SMC 0048)
  - Southwestern Historical Quarterly containing Don Olson's article, 1997 (Folder SMC 0048)
  - "Alvar Nunez Cabeza De Vaca, the First Overland Traveller of European Descent, and his Journey From Florida to the Pacific Coast--1528-1536 Ad." by F. Bandelier. Photocopy (Folder SMC 0048)
- Dorys C. Grover correspondence and articles, 1996; Grover, Dorys Crow
  - Photocopies of essays by Dorys C. Grover which appeared in The Pendleton Record titled " Archie Binns, novelist", "John Alexander Graves III", and Autumn in New England.", 1996 (Folder SMC 0049)
  - Correspondence with John Graves (Folder SMC 0049)
- Alberto M. Ramon galley proof, 1996; Ramon, Alberto M.
  Mexican-American border region -- Fiction
  - Galley proof of On Both Sides of the River by Alberto M. Ramon, 1996 (Folder SMC 0050)
- Roberto A. Galván articles, 1970-1973; Galván, Roberto A.
  - Copies of articles by Galván: "'Chichecano.' Neologismo Jergal", "Resena de Libros", "More on 'Frito' as an English Loan-Word in Mexican Spanish", and "Chicano, Vocablo, Controvertido", 1970-1973 (Folder SMC 0051)
- Larry L. King photograph, 1979; Gent, Jo Ellen
  King, Larry L.
  - Photograph of Larry L. King in Jo Ellen Gent's backyard in Wimberly, TX with a note from Gent [3" x 5"], October 1979 (Folder SMC 0052)
- Texas Hatters cartoon booklet, 1980; Texas Hatters
  Cowboys -- Caricatures and cartoons; Cowboys -- Clothing
  - Booklet titled "The Care and Feeding of the Hat" by M. Gammage, 1980 (Folder SMC 0053)
- Ace Reid Cowpokes merchandise, 1998-2007; Reid, Asa E., 1925-1991
  Cowboys -- Caricatures and cartoons; Cartoonists -- United States
  - Three calendars and playing cards featuring Cowpokes cartoons by Asa "Ace" Reid, 1998-2007 (Folder SMC 0054)
- Ace Reid typescript, circa 1999; Reid, Asa E., 1925-1991
  Cowboys -- Caricatures and cartoons
  - Typescript for Ace Reid and the Cowpokes Cartoons, by Ace Reid, circa 1999 (Folder SMC 0055)
- J. Edwin Smith booklets, 1958; Smith, J. Edwin
  Political campaigns -- United States